<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[NodeBots New Zealand]]></title>
  <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-20T16:07:38+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://nodebots.co.nz/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Gibson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[International NodeBots Day 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/06/20/international-nodebots-day/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-20T15:04:01+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/06/20/international-nodebots-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re back!
<br/>
<br/>
If you live in the Wellington region, come join us on July the 26th to meet other other keen minded, soon to be robot masters and explore the wonderful world of robotics and electronics. This event is run simultaneously around the world as International NodeBots day, we’ll be connecting with other NodeBots events in a heap of different countries to learn and hack together.
<br/>
<br/>
NodeBots day isn’t your typical hackathon, this event is about learning and having fun with electronics using JavaScript. You’ll get to play with LEDs, servos, sensors, Arduinos and maybe even a Raspberry Pi.</p>

<p><a href="https://ti.to/nodebots-new-zealand/international-nodebots-day-2015">Tickets are availble here.</a>
<br/>
<br/></p>

<h4>Who should attend?</h4>

<p>Anyone who has an interest in how things work, be it electronics or programming, anyone with a curious mind will enjoy NodeBots.
<br/>
<br/></p>

<h4>What do I need to bring?</h4>

<p>Yourself, a laptop (if you have one), and some lunch or lunch money.
<br/>
<br/>
You don’t need to bring any hardware, we’ll supply everything you need to build a fully functioning robot. But, if you have any hardware of your own, do bring it along to show off, we’re trying to grow a community and sharing knowledge is an easy win.
<br/>
<br/></p>

<h4>What will we do?</h4>

<p>Anything and everything, the kits supplied have guides to teach from how LEDs work all the way through to making a flappy-cat game on an LCD screen. We’ll be building SumoBots at some stage during the day, and having a SumoBot battle, but to quote John Key, &ldquo;at the end of the day&rdquo; you’re free to build anything you want.
<br/>
<br/></p>

<h4>Can I bring my child?</h4>

<p>Yes, we encourage young minds to come and learn with us, and we’ve frequently had kids from 7-12 join us, but do keep in mind that the guides aren&rsquo;t setup for kids, which means guided learning might be needed; so a guardian will be required to help out.
<br/>
<br/></p>

<h4>What does it cost?</h4>

<p>Thanks to our awesome sponsors, $15.00 is all you need to get a ticket to the event.
<br/>
<br/>
However, if you are financially constrained, we do have a discount that will make the ticket free. The $15 is to cover costs for expendables, it&rsquo;s a small fee but it helps keep us going.
<br/>
<br/>
Looking forward to you joining us on Sunday the 26th for a day of hacking and learning. :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nodebots Wellington]]></title>
    <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/05/10/nodebots-wellington/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-10T13:06:48+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/05/10/nodebots-wellington</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surprise; Where hosting an event here in Wellington on the 23rd of May!!!</p>

<p>If you haven&rsquo;t heard already, NodeBots is a fun event where you get to build robots with JavaScript!</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s right&hellip; if you&rsquo;ve any JavaScript experience, you can now use your powers to manipulate the machines. From <a href="http://instagram.com/p/cFVNtmJxlc/">blinking lights</a> to <a href="http://nodebots.io/sumo.html">Sumo Bot battles</a>, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6NYyGC-wZKU">Remote control cats</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/substack/matador-copter">Bull fighting with quadcopters</a>&hellip;</p>

<p>If you have no idea how to use an LED, have no fear - NodeBot experts will be on hand to help you hack, wire, and solder your way to a full fledged NodeBot. It&rsquo;s aimed for ages 14 and up, but if you&rsquo;re a smart cookie and not quite 14 yet we&rsquo;ll still let you code some robots :D</p>

<p>We have a range of things to build and learn about at our NodeBots events, from messing with <a href="https://twitter.com/PrototypeAlex/status/582070216001077249">sound</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/PrototypeAlex/status/580538795520614401">light</a>, all the way though to building robotic arms to help pickup coffee cups.</p>

<p>The only thing you&rsquo;ll need to bring is yourself and a laptop, and maybe some lunch for the day, we&rsquo;ll supply everything else.</p>

<p>Ticket prices are $15 each, but if you’re a bit cash strapped then use the discount code NODEBOTS_IS_AWESOME, and the ticket will be free. We have low overheads, so as long as there’s a few people paying for tickets, the minimum gets paid, anything left over goes into buying more awesome gear.</p>

<p>Checkout <a href="https://ti.to/nodebots-new-zealand/nodebots-wellington-may">ti.to/nodebots-new-zealand/nodebots-wellington-may</a> for tickets, and hopefully we&rsquo;ll see you there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nodebots Are Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/03/26/nodebots-are-go/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-26T08:11:57+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2015/03/26/nodebots-are-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve hit our sponsorship target, which has enabled us to buy all the gear necessary to run Nodebots events.</p>

<p>And run Nodebots events we have, already we’ve  run a pilot event during a <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Node-js-Wellington/events/221088394/">node.js meet-up</a> in Wellington, which was done in preparation for the <a href="http://christchurch.nodeconf.com">OneShot NodeConf</a> in Christchurch this weekend, in which we’ll be hosting a full day workshop on the Sunday.</p>

<p>Our new sponsors; Xero, TradeMe and MediaSuite and original sponsors (believers); Hoist Apps and Atomic, have all pitched in to make this possible, and it is an incredible feat.</p>

<p>Because of their commitment we have Nodebots nationwide, which is extremely unique, and something no other country in the world has done, or could do. But, since we’re a small country we can ship the gear to any city, relatively cheaply.</p>

<p>So If you’d like to run a Nodebots event in your city or at your event, please get in touch with us via twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nodebots_nz">@nodebots_nz</a>. Our goal is to run as many events as possible, hardware goes out of date quite fast, and we need to get the most out of it before it becomes antique hardware used in a museum.</p>

<p>Thank you all for believing in us, we’ll see you at an event in your town soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2014/09/28/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-28T20:34:35+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://nodebots.co.nz/blog/2014/09/28/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everybody and join me in welcoming to the world the brand spanking new NodeBots New Zealand.</p>

<p>For a while now I&rsquo;ve been planning and working out how to bring NodeBots to New Zealand, and after some sweat and hard work I&rsquo;ve finally started the ball rolling.</p>

<p>Though sadly the initial kickoff Wellington NodeBots event is postponed until further notice, well&hellip; basically until I find one or two more sponsors to help alleviate the cost of the gear and kick the organisation off.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re a company, or know of a company that would be keen on sponsoring, please get in touch, we&rsquo;re so close to pulling off a NodeBots day here in Wellington, and once that&rsquo;s out of the way we&rsquo;ll be hitting up Auckland and possibly a few other cities too. Also, If you&rsquo;d like to help out with the organisation then jump on the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/javascript-new-zealand">Google Group</a> and make yourself known.</p>

<p>Once we find our last sponsors I&rsquo;ll be able to announce some dates, in the mean time, talk about this at the coffee machine / water cooler and hype this thing up! It&rsquo;s gunna be bigger than Jonny Five in the 80s!</p>

<p>Cheerio,
Alex</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
